<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Home on Moritz Friedrich</title><link>https://www.moritzfriedrich.com/</link><description>Recent content in Home on Moritz Friedrich</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 20:43:19 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.moritzfriedrich.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Privacy Policy</title><link>https://www.moritzfriedrich.com/privacy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 22:29:58 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.moritzfriedrich.com/privacy/</guid><description>Preface The following text is only available in German for now, since its required by law and I lack the resources to let a lawyer translate it to english. Therefore, I'll try my best to sum up all those paragraphs of useless text in english below.
Summary I use Cloudflare to improve performance and GitHub Pages to host the site. In fact, it's all openly available here: github.com/Radiergummi/moritzfriedrich.com. There are no moving parts, and I promise to not doing something nefarious.</description></item><item><title>Imprint</title><link>https://www.moritzfriedrich.com/imprint/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 22:11:55 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.moritzfriedrich.com/imprint/</guid><description>Responsible for the content of this website Moritz Friedrich
Wolfratshauserstraße 102
81379 Munich, Germany
Mail: kontakt@moritzfriedrich.com</description></item><item><title>Hello World!</title><link>https://www.moritzfriedrich.com/posts/hello-world/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 20:54:44 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.moritzfriedrich.com/posts/hello-world/</guid><description>Hello darkness, my old friend&amp;hellip;
This is not the first time I'm attempting to write regularly. As it usually happens, you start enthusiastically with a thought or twice at the edge of your brain, eager to be put in words, thinking &amp;ldquo;Oh yeah! This time, I'm going to do it! I'm finally making a blog!&amp;quot; &amp;ndash; until you actually start doing so.
Now, in my previous attempts, one of two things might happen:</description></item><item><title>About Me</title><link>https://www.moritzfriedrich.com/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 20:39:42 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.moritzfriedrich.com/about/</guid><description>Hi! I'm Moritz, a full-stack developer with a focus on the backend side of things. Currently, I'm working for MessengerPeople, a startup from Munich, as the head honcho of the Messaging API.
At MessengerPeople, I've got the opportunity to work on and lead several super interesting projects on the bleeding edge of technology. That includes migrating the existing, legacy PHP (5.6) stack with a homegrown framework onto a solid foundation: After lots of pain and sweat and tears, we're now proud (product) owners of a Kubernetes setup with modern PHP (&amp;gt;=7.</description></item></channel></rss>