<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>blog on Moritz Friedrich</title><link>https://www.moritzfriedrich.com/tags/blog/</link><description>Recent content in blog on Moritz Friedrich</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 12:03:35 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.moritzfriedrich.com/tags/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Taking user feedback seriously</title><link>https://www.moritzfriedrich.com/posts/user-feedback/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 12:03:35 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.moritzfriedrich.com/posts/user-feedback/</guid><description>Recently, I got annoyed with the way we handle support in some cases. Users write emails or send messages via instant messaging apps, which end up in some ticket system, get assigned a priority and will be forwarded as a ticket to a support employee. Maybe they don't have time right away because they are busy or on vacation or don't like the customer or simply aren't too motivated that day.</description></item><item><title>Automatically deployed feature branch previews</title><link>https://www.moritzfriedrich.com/posts/feature-branch-previews/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2020 13:12:20 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.moritzfriedrich.com/posts/feature-branch-previews/</guid><description>Automatically deployed feature branch previews At MessengerPeople, we have employed a pretty strict branching schema:
/───fix/foo──o──\ / \ / \ master ━━┯━━━x━━━━x━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━x━━┯━━━━━━━━━━━━x━━┯━━━━━━━━━ │ \ │ / │ │ \ │ / │ │ \───feature/bar─o─o─o────o─│───o──o──/ │ │ │ │ v1.24.8 v1.24.9 v1.25.0 x: Merge/Branch o: Commit There's a single branch and source of truth, which is master. Every Release is a tag on master, every new development takes place in a new branch.</description></item><item><title>Embracing Imperfection</title><link>https://www.moritzfriedrich.com/posts/embracing-imperfection/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 10:54:09 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.moritzfriedrich.com/posts/embracing-imperfection/</guid><description>Ah, source code. Usually, and especially if written by someone else, it's awful. If you suffer from even a slight proclivity to perfectionism, you will inevitably try to refactor it. While doing so, you will equally inevitably realize there's even bigger fruits to reap a little further up, and before you know it you're rewriting the entire application. Now, the younger me might have said, &amp;ldquo;obviously that was necessary!&amp;quot;, utterly ignoring the fact that the end result performs equally well at best, with a ridiculous amount of time having been wasted on playing a zero-sum game.</description></item><item><title>Simple Cronjobs for CLI apps using systemd</title><link>https://www.moritzfriedrich.com/posts/php-cronjobs/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2020 13:29:13 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.moritzfriedrich.com/posts/php-cronjobs/</guid><description>Most applications will need some kind of asynchronous processing happening in the background: Calculating statistics, sending emails or processing large files. These tasks are probably abstracted into some kind of job queue, ready to be fetched by a worker.
Now, whenever you want to perform a task in regular intervals (say: Calculating monthly billing positions and sending them to Stripe for invoicing), you need some kind of scheduler. The most straightforward and probably most common solution is to simply create a cron job.</description></item><item><title>Hello World!</title><link>https://www.moritzfriedrich.com/posts/hello-world/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 20:54:44 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.moritzfriedrich.com/posts/hello-world/</guid><description>Hello darkness, my old friend&amp;hellip;
This is not the first time I'm attempting to write regularly. As it usually happens, you start enthusiastically with a thought or twice at the edge of your brain, eager to be put in words, thinking &amp;ldquo;Oh yeah! This time, I'm going to do it! I'm finally making a blog!&amp;quot; &amp;ndash; until you actually start doing so.
Now, in my previous attempts, one of two things might happen:</description></item></channel></rss>